# Oleg Ryakhovsky

E-mail: <u>oleg.ryakhovsky@gmail.com</u>

2326wz@gmail.com

Phone: +7 915 483 08 10

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/2326wz/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/2326wz/</a>

#### **PROFILE**

Deal with Deep Learning, Computer Vision and Machine learning over one year. Started carrier as Telecommunications engineer, worked a lot with statistics of cellular networks, then came to data analysis and development area.

Interested in future development as a Data Scientist, preferably in fields of Computer Vision or Big Data Analysis.

 $Addicted\ to\ ml4sg\ ideas,\ collaborate\ at\ Lacmus\ DL\ project\ \underline{https://lacmus-foundation.github.io/}\ .$ 

## **PROJECTS**

# 1. "Sharp-In": Deep learning solution for improvement of poor quality drone images

Practically used in rescue of lost people in wild territories.

https://github.com/lacmus-foundation/sharp-in

2. Augmented	d c	lataset	prepara	ation	pro	ects:
--------------	-----	---------	---------	-------	-----	-------

Image Inpainting:

Bounding Boxes crop utility:

https://github.com/lacmus-foundation/lacmus/tree/master/data\_utils/ImgGenerator https://github.com/lacmus-foundation/lacmus/tree/master/data\_utils/bboxCropper

#### **KAGGLE**

Fraud detection (ML):	https://www.kaggle.com/c/ieee-fraud-detection		
Image recognition (DL):	https://www.kaggle.com/c/hotdogornot		
Others:	https://www.kaggle.com/caba7005452/competitions		

### **SKILLS**

Languages:	#Python #SQL
Libraries:	#Keras #pandas #sklearn #LGBM #Pytorch #Tensorflow #matplotlib #XGboost #CatBoost #OpenCV #numpy

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

NOKIA NETWORKS - Automation systems developer	2018 - now
Analyzed bottlenecks and time losses in equipment delivery process. Based on analysis:	
<ul> <li>Created an ML tool for delivery delays prediction.</li> <li>Wrote and implemented numerous handy tools to improve efficiency of logistic staff.</li> <li>Developed a server based application for: a) automated collection, generation and distribution of different progress reports, b) automated sending of action reminders to process stakeholders, c) running minor scheduled processes in company's intranet.</li> <li>Wrote an application for running transactions in SAP to eliminate manual work.</li> </ul> As a result I'm saving to company over 5000 man-hours per year.	
HUAWEI Tech.Co - Managed Services Procurement department, leader	2014 - 2018
Wrote applications for tenders results analysis and visualization.	
<ul> <li>Improved contracts preparation process with saving apx 2 man-hours per one contract by mean of simple code.</li> </ul>	
PromKompozit, OOO - Engineer	2013 - 2014
• Developed an application for analysis of possible angular velocity of spinning airplane based on airframe and foil parameters.	
NOKIA NETWORKS - Radio network expert	2004 – 2012
<ul> <li>Projecting, analysis and optimization of 2G-3G networks</li> </ul>	2004 – 2012
Vimpelcom, OAO - Radio network statistics engineer	2002 - 2004
Statistical analysis and optimization of 2G networks	
Ericsson Russia – Radio network engineer	2000 - 2002
Projecting of 2G networks	

## **EDUCATION**

Moscow Power Engineering Institute - Qualified as Radio Engineer		
Machine learning and Deep learning courses at ODS.ai	2019	